Kwame Ampoma - Mensah

Senior Front-End Enginner

Mobile: +233 267 626 632 Email: kamensqh@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/kamensq Website: https://kamensqh.com/

OBJECTIVE

I'm a Front-End engineer with over 7 years of experience in all aspects of front-end development but currently using React (NextJS) and React Native to deliver the best user-centered products. I'm good at working with different teams to solve problems and impact organizational outcomes positively.

Skills

JavaScript NextJS

Typescript React - Native

NodeJS Storybook

State Management Redux

Context

CSS Frameworks Tailwind

Bootstrap

Database MongoDB

Authentication NextAuth, KeyCloak

API RESTful

CI/CD Git

Others Web Development

Team player

UI/UX

EDUCATION

Methodist University College

Accra - Ghana

BSc Degree in Information Technology

Sept 2009 - Sept 2014

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Front-End Developer

May 2018 - Till Date

Hubtel limited

- Led development team of 4 front-end engineers to build a consumer and vendor portal for the Electricity Company of Ghana using NextJS and Bootstrap. The goal was to efficiently sell power to citizens securely and manage issue reporting for more than 1 million daily active users and a workforce of over 10,000 staff.
- Collaborated with the design team to build a brand guide and design system so theres
 consistent look and feel across all platforms and also cut down development time by 30%
 using NPM and Storybook.js for reusable components.
- Rebuilt our main e-commerce web app from PHP to Vue.js. The goal was to increase the number of items a user could see per session and enhance their overall experience. This increased sales by 40%
- Worked with product managers to ensure maximum delivery of value by using agile and scrum methodology to keep projects ontrack and prioritze work increasing
- Led daily stand-ups to ensure the team worked efficiently and provided visibility into the state of a development project which helped plan more effectively, and adjust strategies based on more hard information and less speculation.
- Worked with Quality Assurance to get new products/features tested and addressed any issues within 48 hours. This lead to 100% bug-free development
- Introduced Sonarqube into our azure builds for continuous inspection of code quality and detect bugs

Front-End Engineer

May 2023 - Nov 2023

RightCom

- Developed a digital signage software incorporating content, screen and schedule management functionalities. This software is designed for companies that share content on screens with customers across various locations, such as banks and telecommunication offices.
- Implemented Keycloak authentication as the primary login method for all RightCom applications using ReactJS.
- Rewrote HTML to meet industry and company standards for SEO and Accessibility. This
 drove a 100% increase in users by appearing on the first page of Google search results.

Front-End Engineer

June 2016 - May 2017

Cobalt Partners

- Translated UX wireframes into design-perfect, responsive, interactive web pages, using HTML/CSS and Bootstrap.
- Improve website load time to as low as possible by implementing optimization techniques including code refactoring, image compression, and caching.
- Built the company website using HTML and CSS, which was transformed into a WordPress platform to facilitate easy content management.